[MUSIC]
[음악]
In the lectures, Emily talked about nearest neighbor models and
강의에서 에밀리가 최근접 이웃 모델과
how they can be used for document retrieval.
이를 통한 문서 검색을 설명했습니다
So today, we're gonna actually do some cool document retrievals
오늘은 간단한 최근접 이웃 모델을 통한
using simple nearest neighbor models.
멋진 문서 검색을 해보죠
Next we're going to build
이제 문서 검색을 위해
a nearest neighbor model for document retrieval.
최근접 이웃 모델을 구축합니다
And here we go, nearest neighbor model for
최근접 이웃 모델입니다
Again, you could implement your own, but we have one already implemented
다시 한 번 말씀드리면 직접 구현해도 되지만 이미 사용 가능한 버전이 구현되어 있으니
here that you can use, which is great for this first course.
첫 강의이니만큼 써도 나쁘지 않을 것 같습니다
We're gonna use the one from the offline, and it is called nearest_neighbors.
graphlab에서 nearest_neighbors을 호출합니다
And just like that use the verb create to create a nearest neighbor model.
다른 모델과 같이 create을 통해 최근접 이웃 모델을 생성합니다
So we're gonna give it this input.
인물 표를 입력으로
The people table.
넣습니다
And we have to say what features we're gonna use in the nearest neighbors.
최근접 이웃에 쓸 특징을 지정해줘야 합니다
So the features are gonna be the tfidf, tfidf.
특징은 TF-IDF가 됩니다
Just like we've been using for the cosine distances above.
위에서 코사인 거리를 쟀을 때와 같습니다
And I'm going to provide a label column and
라벨에 이름을
this label column is going to be the name.
넣습니다
So when I return my nearest neighbors, it's going to
최근접 이웃을 반환할 때 최근접 이웃의 실제 라벨인
return the actual label of the nearest neighbor, so the name of the person.
인물의 이름을 반환하게 됩니다
And that will make the print out prettier.
이렇게 하면 출력이 깔끔해집니다
So that's cool that it's there for us.
이왕 있으니 써먹는 게 좋을 것 같습니다
So it should only take a few seconds.
몇 초면 됩니다
And we will have, now there we are.
이제 나올 텐데, 나왔네요
We will have a nearest neighbor model for document retrieval.
문서 검색을 위한 최근접 이웃 모델입니다
So now we can use it, so let's go ahead and use it.
이제 한 번 써보죠
So I'm going to just create another header here and
헤더를 또 하나 만들어서
say applying the nearest-neighbors model for
검색을 위해 최근접 이웃 모델 적용하기라고
retrieval, and let's see what we get.
쓰고 어떻게 되는지 봅니다
So the first question is, so let's do our first query.
첫 질의를 해봅시다
So who is closest to Obama?
누가 오바마와 가장 가까운가요?
So who are the closest people to Obama in the data set.
데이터 세트에서 오바마와 가장 가까운 인물을 알고 싶습니다
So if you just take our neighbor model,
이웃 모델에서 query 메소드를 사용하면
we can use the method query, the function query associated with it,
특정 입력에 대한
which just queries the model with some input.
질의를 실행하게 됩니다
So in this case Obama as our input, and gives me back the nearest-neighbor.
오바마가 입력이 되고 최근접 이웃이 반환됩니다
So where the nearest-neighbor is to Obama, we'll compute it, and it's very quick.
최근접 이웃이 누군지 계산하면 금방 나옵니다
And I say, okay, the closest person to Obama is Obama himself, which makes sense.
오바마와 가장 가까운 인물은 오바마 자신입니다. 그거 말 되네요
But after that, we have Joe Biden, who is the current US vice president.
그다음으로는 조 바이든 현 미국 부통령입니다
So the president is closest to the vice president.
그러므로 대통령은 부통령과 가장 가깝습니다
And then we find a few other politicians, including former president Bill Clinton,
그다음에는 전 대통령 빌 클린턴을 포함해
which we saw above.
위에서 본 몇몇 정치인들이 보이네요
[MUSIC]
[음악]